Inventory of the Papers of Hardy Cross Dillard
University of Virginia, Arthur J. Morris Law Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
Inventory of the Papers of Hardy Cross Dillard
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
MSS 84-8
This collections consists of 64 boxes.
The papers of Hardy Cross Dillard span 1925-1981 and document his career as law professor, legal scholar, and dean of the University of Virginia School of Law; his career in the U.S. Army during and after World War II; and his years as judge on the International Court of Justice. There is extensive correspondence with other scholars, particularly in the fields of international law and political science, and with other ICJ judges.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The papers of Hardy Cross Dillard, 1925-1981, were deposited at the Law Library by his widow, Valgerdur Dillard, on 31 October 1984.
Biographical/Historical Information
Hardy Cross Dillard was born in New Orleans in 1902, the second son of Dr. James H. Dillard and Avarene Budd Dillard. Dr. Dillard, a professor of mathematics, literature and classics, also served as dean at Tulane University. In 1911 the family moved to Paris where Hardy learned French and received his early schooling. Later the family settled in Charlottesville, and Hardy spent most of his preparatory school years at Virginia Episcopal School in Lynchburg. After one year at the University of Virginia, he transferred in 1920 to the U.S. Military Academy. Upon graduation in 1924, he returned to the University of Virginia to study law.
During his law school years, Hardy was an outstanding student and an editor of the Virginia Law Review. After graduation in 1927, he accepted the invitation to serve as acting professor at the Law School for a couple of years. He then spent a year practicing law in New York and a year as a Carnegie Endowment Fellow at the University of Paris before returning to teach law at Virginia where he would remain a member of the faculty until retirement in 1968. Dillard taught and wrote on the subjects of contracts, international law, and jurisprudence, among others. In time he became one of the best loved and most respected members of the Law School community in the twentieth century. In 1963 he began a five-year term as dean. A couple of years after his retirement he was appointed judge on the International Court of Justice at The Hague where he served until 1979.
In tandem with his career in legal education, Dillard had a military career. In 1942 he offered his service to the U.S. Army and quickly achieved the rank of colonel, serving in Europe and the Far East. For many years after the war, he held various advisory positions at the National War College and the U.S. Air Force Academy.
During the turbulent years following the Supreme Court's decision in Brown v. Board of Education, Dillard took a leadership role in opposing Virginia's advocates of massive resistance. In 1955 he argued for the defense before the Virginia Supreme Court in Almond v. Day, a case testing the legality of laws giving veterans' orphans grants to be used for either public or private schooling. Virginia's Comptroller Day had refused to pay these grants on the grounds that they were unconstitutional, and the Court agreed. Through the 1960s Dillard worked determinedly in support of the integration of Virginia's public schools.
Hardy Dillard married Janet Schauffler, and they had a daughter, Joan, and a son, Hardy. Janet died in 1970, and two years later Hardy married Valgerdur Dent. He died in Charlottesville in 1982.
Chronology of Hardy Cross Dillard's Life
1902 Born in New Orleans, Louisiana on 23 October to James Hardy and Avarene Lippincott Budd Dillard
1911-1912 Lived in France and attended a French Lycee
1915-1916 Attended high school in Charlottesville, Virginia
1916-1919 Attended and graduated from Virginia Episcopal School, Lynchburg, Va.
1919-1920 Attended University of Virginia
1920-1924 Attended and graduated from United States Military Academy
1924-1927 Attended and graduated from University of Virginia Law School
1926 Summer law clerk, Price, Smith and Spillman, Charleston, W. Va.
1927 Admitted to Virginia Bar
1927-1929 Acting Assistant Professor, University of Virginia Law School
1928 Travelled in England, France, Italy and Algiers
1929-1930 Practiced law at Gregg and Church, New York, N.Y.
1930-31 Carnegie Endowment Fellow, (Faculte de droit,) University of Paris
1931-1933 Acting assistant (associate?) professor, University of Virginia Law School
1932, -33 Summer associate, Davis, Polk, Wardell, Gardiner and Reed, New York, N.Y.
1933-38 Associate Professor, University of Virginia School of Law
1934 Married Janet Gray Schauffler
1935 Birth of Joan Jarvis Dillard
1937-1940 Assistant Dean, University of Virginia Law School
1937-1940 Advisory Editor, Virginia Quarterly Review
1938-1970 Professor, University of Virginia Law School
1937 Birth of Hardy Schauffler Dillard
1938- 1942 Director, Institute of Public Affairs
1942 Major, U.S. Army; promoted to Lt. Colonel, same year
1942-1945 Received command and staff assignments in Europe and Far East; awarded Legion of Merit with Oak Leaf Cluster and Bronze Star Medal
1943 Promoted to Colonel, U.S. Army
1943-1944 Director of Academic Instruction, School for Military Government
1946 First Director of Studies, National War College
1947-1950 Consultant, Brookings Institution
1947 Resumed teaching at University of Virginia Law School
1948 Colonel, U.S. Army Reserve
1949-52 Member of Board of Consultants, National War College
1949 Member, Civilian Advisory Group, National War College
1950 Active duty in International Section, Pentagon; Legal Consultant, Office of High Commissioner for Germany; Lecturer, France and Germany
1951-1954 Member, Board of Consultants, National War College
1952-1961 Trustee, Virginia Episcopal School
1953 Fulbright Lecturer, Oxford University
1953-1957 Summer active duty, Judge Advocate General's School
1956 Civilian Consultant, Army War College
1956-1962 Editor, Virginia Bar News
1957 Carnegie Lecturer, Hague Academy of International Law
1957 Recipient, Raven Award
1957 Consultant, NATO Defense College in France
1958-1970 James Monroe Professor of Law, University of Virginia Law School
1962 Secretary, Defense Committee on Non-technical Instruction in Armed Forces
1962 Lecturer, Egyptian Society of International Law and University of Cairo
1962-1963 Visiting Professor of Law, Columbia University
1962-1963 President, American Society of International Law
1963- 1979 Member of Council, American Law Institute
1963- 1968 Dean, University of Virginia Law School
1965 Member, Virginia Magna Charta Commission
1965 Member, Special Advisory Committee, Air Force Academy
1966-1970 Permanent Advisory Council, Air Force Academy
1966 Sibley Lecturer, University of Georgia
1967 Recipient, Thomas Jefferson Award, University of Virginia
1967 Member, UNESCO Committee on the Role of UNESCO in the Teaching and Dissemination of International Law
1967 Tucker Lecturer, Washington and Lee Law School
1967 Bailey Lecturer, Louisiana State University
1968 Member, Virginia Commission on Constitution Revision
1970 Recipient of Distinguished Civilian Award, U.S. Air Force
1970-1979 Judge, International Court of Justice, The Hague
1970 Death of Janet Schauffler Dillard
1971 Member, Arbitral Tribunal, Beagle Channel Case between Chile and Argentina
1971 Recipient of Honorary Degree, Tulane University
1972 Married Valgerdur Nielsen Dent
1976 Recipient of Honorary Degree, Washington College, Maryland
1977 Mooers Lecturer, American University
1979 Recipient of the Wolfgang Friedman Memorial Award, Columbia University
1979 Honorary President, American Law Institute
1982 Died on 12 May in Charlottesville, Virginia
1989 Hardy S. Dillard died in February
Scope and Content Information
The papers of Hardy Cross Dillard 1925-1981 were deposited at the Law Library by his widow, Valgerdur Dillard, on 31 October 1984. Most of the records had been stored in file cabinets in the basement of their home. The only part of the collection not found organized in labeled folders was the correspondence dated after 1970; from that point on, Judge Dillard usually did not have secretarial help, so he frequently typed his own letters and kept his files in re-cycled folders.
The labeled folders were arranged in three groups: the oldest, ca. 1930-1960, were comprised of personal and professional correspondence, teaching materials, and law practice files; the second, dating from 1963-1968 when Dillard was dean of the Law School, were of the same nature as the first; and the third, dating from 1970 to 1979, relate to his work on the International Court of Justice. These three groups of subject files have been interfiled alphabetically. The unfoldered correspondence has been filed under the heading "Personal: Correspondence" and arranged chronologically in 80 folders. This material is found in Series I.
The speeches and writings were isolated and arranged alphabetically by title or subject. The folders contain whatever related material was found with the piece. These files, comprising Series II, are especially revealing of the way Dillard worked. He was a popular teacher and speaker whose anecdotes and paradigms seemed to flow spontaneously, but his papers show this was not entirely the case. Articles, speeches, opinions, and even some letters went through many drafts handwritten in pencil on legal pads.
Series I
SERIES DESCRIPTION
The subject files provide remarkably even coverage of the various facets of Dillard's long career in law and legal education. Predictably dominant are files concerning teaching at the Law School (1927-70) and at several Department of Defense colleges (1946-69). Other files concern his military work include the establishment of the School of Military Government in Charlottesville during World War II, and his related assignments in Europe, as well as his advisory work for the Air Force Academy during the 1960's. Trips to, and related projects on, China, Germany and other European countries are documented. There are files concerning his involvement in such professional organizations as the Association of American Law Schools, the American Bar Association, the American Law Institute, and the American Society of International Law, of which he was president in 1962-63. Sprinkled throughout the collection are materials regarding certain aspects of University life, including several folders on the Honor System. The records of Dillard's term as dean of the Law school are relatively thin because most of them are in the Dean's Papers in the Law School Archives. Dillard's occasional practice of law is documented in several boxes of case material. There are several boxes of International Court of Justice files in Mss 84-8, but the bulk of those records are in Mss 84-8a. Finally, files of a more personal nature include general correspondence and documentation of advisory work for organizations such as the Virginia Quarterly Review and the Virginia Episcopal School, as well as the extensive personal correspondence files (1925-81). Files labelled "Personal" concern strictly family matters. Interested researchers should consult the Dillard Family papers at Alderman Library for documentation of the lives of Hardy's parents and other relatives.
Series II
Description
This series contains files of speeches (1949-80) and articles (1942-78). Speech topics include international law and the world court, military issues, law school matters, legal education, civil rights and civic concerns. The articles center around matters of jurisprudence and international law and are followed by reviews of books on issues of international law.
Contents List
- Active Duty--JAG Theses 1954 Sept. (Box 1)
- Advisory Committee: NATO Defense College 1957 (Box 1)
- Aesthetics n.d. (Box 1)
- Air Force Academy 1965-68 (Box 1)
  - Advisory Council 1966-69, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Advisory Council's Final Report 1965 May (Box 1)
  - Clippings ca. 1965 (Box 1)
  - Miscellany 1966-1969 (Box 1)
- Air War College 1960-1969, 2 folders (Box 2)
- Air War College--AFA Honor Code Study 1966 (Box 2)
- Alumni Association (Dean's File as Secretary) 1965-67 (Box 2)
- Alumni Association Dinner for HCD 1969-70 (Box 2)
- Alumni File: Dillard Fund 1968-69 (Box 2)
- American Academy of Political and Social Science 1969 (Box 2)
- American Arbitration Association 1966-67 (Box 2)
- American Bar Association (ABA): Bar Examination 1966 (Box 2)
- ABA: Committe on Education about Communism 1963-1968 (Box 2)
- ABA: HCD (Personal) 1964-68 (Box 2)
- ABA: ICJ Selection Committee 1980 (Box 2)
- ABA: Law and Security Committee 1979, 4 folders (Box 3)
- ABA: Meeting in Atlanta 1976 (Box 3)
- Municipal Law Section 1935-40 (Box 3)
- ABA: Portland Meeting 1979 (Box 3)
- American Bar Foundation 1966-69 (Box 3)
- American Journal of International Law(AJIL) 1961-69, 2 folders (Box 4)
- AJIL--Miscellany 1978-79 (Box 4)
- American Law Book Company: Legal Bibliography 1932-34 (Box 4)
- American Law Institute (ALI) 1968-69 (Box 4)
- ALI: Association of American Law Schools 1933 (Box 4)
- ALI: Helms Letter 1966-67 (Box 4)
- ALI: Miscellany 1975-81, 2 folders (Box 4)
- ALI-ABA: Houston Conference 1981 (Box 5)
- American Society of International Law (ASIL) 1963-1969, 2 folders (Box 5)
- ASIL: AJIL 1962 (Box 5)
- ASIL: Annual Meeting 1962 (Box 5)
- ASIL: Bar Admission Policy 1960 (Box 5)
- ASIL: Briggs, Herbert (Circular Letter) 1960 (Box 5)
- ASIL: Committees 1961, -62, 2 folders (Box 5)
- ASIL: Miscellaneous Committee Correspondence 1960 (Box 5)
- ASIL: Committee Documents 1961-62 (Box 5)
- ASIL: Cornell Meeting 1960 June (Box 6)
- ASIL: Correspondence re Federalism 1961-62 (Box 6)
- ASIL: Executive Committee 1963 (Box 6)
- ASIL: Executive Council 1958-62, -81, 3 folders (Box 6)
- ASIL: 50th Anniversary Annual Meeting 1956 Mar. (Box 6)
- ASIL: Ford Foundation Grant 1961 (Box 6)
- ASIL: ICJ Nomination 1960 (Box 7)
- ASIL: Miscellaneous 1960, 4 folders (Box 7)
- ASIL: Newsletters 1962 (Box 7)
- ASIL: Presidency 1962 (Box 7)
- ASIL: Program Committee 1961 (Box 7)
- ASIL: Regular Meeting 1955-56 (Box 7)
- Armed Forces Industrial College 1949-50 (Box 7)
- Armed Forces Staff College 1956-69, 2 folders (Box 7)
- Army Operations Research Office 1960-61 (Box 8)
- Army: Reserve Duty 1952; 1954-61, 2 folders (Box 8)
- "Army Stuff" [Civil Affairs/Military Government Course Materials] 1951-1962 (Box 8)
- Army War College 1951-52; 1963 (Box 8)
- Army War College (Armed Forces Staff College): JAG School Teaching Material 1959-61 (Box 8)
- Army War College: Correspondence 1947-60 (Box 8)
- Army War College: Lecture Notes [1967-68] (Box 8)
- Association of American Law Schools (AALS) 1935-36 (Box 8)
- AALS: Appraisal Committee 1966 (Box 8)
- AALS: Committee on Graduate Instruction 1965 (Box 8)
- AALS: Committee on Legal Education for Negroes 1964-67, 3 folders (Box 9)
- AALS: Contracts Committee 1949 (Box 9)
- AALS: Executive Committee 1965-68, 3 folders (Box 9)
- AALS: Financial Committee 1965-68 (Box 9)
- AALS: Florida Inspection 1964 (Box 10)
- AALS: Government Relations Committee 1968-69 (Box 10)
- AALS: Humanities Committee 1966-69, 2 folders (Box 10)
- AALS: Incorporation 1966 (Box 10)
- AALS: Meeting n Chicago 1952 (Box 10)
- AALS: Miscellaneous 1969-79 (Box 10)
- AALS: U.S.-Soviet Conference 1965 (Box 10)
- Bailey Lecture 1967 (Box 10)
- Battle Case 1957 (Box 10)
- Behavioral Science Correspondence [for Law and Behavioral Science Conference] 1956 (Box 10)
- Bendetson Report 1963 (Box 10)
- Beta Theta Pi 1954 (Box 10)
- Beukena, Col. [Bureau of Public Relations] 1941-42 (Box 10)
- Bibliography n.d. (Box 10)
- Bowman, A.C. 1951 (Box 10)
- Bricker Amendment 1954 (Box 10)
- Broadside of a new book on socialism [1930's] (Box 10)
- Brookings Institution 1947-54, 4 folders (Box 10)
- Brooks, Cleanth: Text of talk, "Poetry in the Age of Anxiety;" marked by HCD 1947 (Box 10)
- Building File 1968 (Box 10)
- Buxton, Joseph E. 1950-52 (Box 10)
- Buxton Memorial (Alumni Fund) 1955 (Box 11)
- Carter, Henry 1951-52 (Box 11)
- Center for Oceans Law and Policy 1978 (Box 11)
- China 1966, 2 folders (Box 11)
- China: Notes and Clippings re Sino-Japanese War 1932-33 (Box 11)
- China Recognition 1954, -66, 4 folders (Box 11)
- China Trip 1945, 4 folders (Box 12)
- Civil Affairs/Military Government [Miscellaneous Notes and Documents] 1945-56 (Box 12)
- Civil Affairs/Military Government Study 1950-51 (Box 12)
- Civil Affairs Holding and Staging Area: Correspondence 1945 (Box 12)
- Civil Affairs Holding and Staging Area: Planning 1945 (Box 12)
- Civil Affairs Training 1942-45 (Box 12)
- Civil Disobedience [and the Vietnam Question] 1966-68 (Box 12)
- Clippings: Miscellaneous [1920-1980], 2 folders (Box 13)
- Columbia University 1962-62 (Box 13)
- Commission on Constitutional Revision (CCR) 1967-69, 2 folders (Box 13)
- CCR: Memo on Section 16 [now sect. 15: Qualities necessary to preservation of free government] [c. 1968] (Box 13)
- Committee on Non-Military Instruction 1962, 2 folders (Box 13)
- Committee on Non-Military Instruction: Clippings 1962 (Box 13)
- Conferences 1948 (Box 14)
- Conference on Ethics and Foreign Policy 1977 (Box 14)
- Conference: "France, Her Allies, and the Future" 1958 (Box 14)
- Conference: "Law and the Behavioral Sciences" 1956 (Box 14)
- Conference: "The Presidency and the International Environment" 1980 (Box 14)
- Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion 1952 (Box 14)
- Congratulatory Letters to New Partners 1964-69 (Box 14)
- Continuing Legal Education (CLE) 1960, 2 folders (Box 14)
- CLE: Practical Lawyer File 1969 (Box 14)
- Contracts: Correspondence 1933-41 (Box 14)
- Contractual Relations Committee 1960-64 (Box 14)
- Council on Foreign Relations 1951 (Box 14)
- Cranberg File 1968 (Box 14)
- Dobie, A.M. 1963-1965 (Box 14)
- Cuban Crisis 1964 (Box 14)
- Draft Act 1942 (Box 14)
- Egypt Trip 1962 (Box 14)
- England Trip: Correspondence 1953 (Box 14)
- Estoppel: Ford Case n.d. (Box 14)
- Faculty Senate: Athletics Committee 1954 (Box 14)
- F.B.I.: Confidential n.d. (Box 14)
- Federalism Conference 1962 (Box 15)
- Finnegan, Mark 1956 (Box 15)
- Ford Foundation Faculty Fellowship 1962-63 (Box 15)
- France Trip 1944-45 (Box 15)
- Fulbright Conference n.d. (Box 15)
- Fulbright Program 1950-51 (Box 15)
- Gag Law 1963 (Box 15)
- German Course 1950 (Box 15)
- German Students: Bibliography and Study Program [1948?] (Box 15)
- German Students: Correspondence 1951-52, 3 folders (Box 15)
- German Students: Financial Records 1951-52 (Box 15)
- German Students: Housing 1951 (Box 15)
- German Students: Insurance 1951-52 (Box 15)
- German Students: Memoranda 1951-52 (Box 16)
- German Students: Records and Applications 1951 (Box 16)
- German Students: Travel 1951 (Box 16)
- German Trainee Program #3 (Planning Reports) 1951-52 (Box 16)
- Germany Trip 1950-51, 3 folders (Box 16)
- Germany Trip: Lectures, Notes [1950] (Box 16)
- Germany Trip: Report 1950-51 (Box 16)
- Guenther, Alfred M. 1949-51 (Box 16)
- Hague Ideas n.d. (Box 16)
- Heller Bill 1940 (Box 16)
- Holmes-Pollock Correspondence (Quotes) n.d. (Box 16)
- Honor Committee: Dean Case 1960-61 (Box 16)
- Honor Committee: Notes 1928 (Box 16)
- Honor System 1968 (Box 16)
- Honor System: Crosby Case 1934-39 (Box 16)
- Hopkins Project (Military Government) 1958 (Box 16)
- Humanities Council: AALS 1968-69 (Box 16)
- "Human Rights Covenant" 1953 (Box 16)
- Immigration 1964 (Box 16)
- Institute of Air and Space Law 1963-64 (Box 17)
- Institute of Public Affairs 1950, -52, 3 folders (Box 17)
- International Cooperation Year (ICY) 1965 (Box 17)
- International Court of Justice (ICJ): Bulletin 1970-77 (Box 17)
- ICJ: Confidential Information Bulletin 1978-81, 3 folders (Box 18)
- ICJ: Department of State Study 1969-70 (Box 18)
- ICJ: Dillard Correspondence 1969-70 (Box 18)
- ICJ: Dillard Handwritten Notes [1971-78] (Box 18)
- ICJ: Dillard Notes on books n.d. (Box 18)
- ICJ: Dillard Statements 1971-76 (Box 18)
- ICJ: Dillard Suggested Emendations n.d. (Box 18)
- ICJ: Great Britain v. France (Draft Decision) 1977 (Box 18)
- ICJ: Iran Case 1979, 2 folders (Box 19)
- ICJ: Material for Gros Article [1979] (Box 19)
- ICJ: Miscellaneous Confidential Documents 1975-81 (Box 19)
- ICJ: Miscellaneous Documents 1971-81, 3 folders (Box 19)
- ICJ: Miscellaneous Published Documents 1971-81 (Box 20)
- ICJ: Printed Material 1960's-70's (Box 20)
- ICJ: Registrar's Notes on Cases 1970, -76, -77 (Box 20)
- ICJ: Speeches by Others 1973-81 (Box 20)
- ICJ: Tudor v. Romania 1979 (Box 20)
- ICJ: U.S. v. Canada (Gulf of Maine Case) 1979 (Box 20)
- International Law: Correspondence 1940 (Box 20)
- Interstate Crime Commission 1935 (Box 20)
- Interuniversity Communication Council (INTERCOM) 1965 (Box 20)
- Introductions 1940 (Box 21)
- Johnson, Joseph E. 1951 (Box 21)
- Judge Advocate General (JAG)--2 weeks: Teaching Material 1953 (Box 21)
- Katz, Milton 1967 (Box 21)
- Kolb, C.E.M.: "The Jurisprudence of Judge H. C. Dillard" 1978 (Box 21)
- Law Day 1959-69, 3 folders (Box 21)
- Law School 1948-49 (Box 21)
- Law School: Administration 1967 (Box 21)
- Law School Business (while HCD was on leave at Columbia) 1963 (Box 21)
- Law School: Committee to Select a Dean 1967 (Box 21)
- Law School: Curriculum Committee 1941, n.d. (Box 21)
- Law School: Dean's Correspondence 1968 (Box 21)
- Law School: Faculty Recommendations [1952] (Box 21)
- Law School Foundation 1955 (1960-69), -77, 3 folders (Box 22)
- Law School: "The Purpose of the Institution" 1964 (Box 22)
- Law School: Library Committee 1948-79, 5 folders (Box 22)
- Law School: Memoranda, Report, Committees, etc 1955-81 (Box 22)
- "Lawyers for Johnson and Humphrey" 1968 (Box 22)
- Leebrick, K. C. 1950 (Box 23)
- Legal Writing: Dillard Fellows 1979 (Box 23)
- Leibman, Morris 1968-69 (Box 23)
- Letters of Credit [1947] (Box 23)
- Long-term Contracts [HCD--S.H. Mudd] 1950 (Box 23)
- Magna Carta Commission 1965 (Box 23)
- Marine Corps Schools 1965-67 (Box 23)
- Mason, Armistead M. 1963-65 (Box 23)
- McDougal, Myres 1963-68 (Box 23)
- Memorabilia: Personal and/or UVa related 1878-1979 (Box 23)
- Military Government 1945 (Box 23)
- Military Government Information 1942-45 (Box 23)
- Military Government-Japan [1945] (Box 23)
- [Miscellaneous] "Future Attention--Delayed" 1979 (Box 23)
- "Miscellaneous and Need"--[Notes, Research] n.d., 1967 (Box 23)
- Mississippi Case 1968-69 (Box 23)
- Monroe Bicentennial Commission: Correspondence 1958 (Box 23)
- Moore, John Bassett 1931-39 (Box 23)
- Mummery, David 1969 (Box 23)
- National War College (NWC): Copies c. 1946, n.d. (Box 24)
- NWC: Correspondence 1946-52; -62, -68, 4 folders (Box 24)
- NWC: Course Changes, First Semester 1951 (Box 24)
- NWC: Curriculum 1946 (Box 24)
- NWC: Curriculum Suggestions 1946 (Box 24)
- NWC: Dillard's Notebook 1946 (Box 24)
- NWC: Gen. Gruenther 1947-48 (Box 24)
- NWC: Kennan Project 1946-47 (Box 25)
- NWC: Lecture Program and Schedules 1946 (Box 25)
- NWC: Military Government 1952-56 (Box 25)
- NWC: Teaching Materials 1946, 4 folders (Box 25)
- NWC: "Security in the Atomic Age" 1947 (Box 25)
- NWC: Seminar Topics c. 1946 (Box 25)
- NWC: Speech Notes 1957-62 (Box 26)
- NWC: Spring Trip 1947 (Box 26)
- NWC: Symposium 1946 (Box 26)
- NWC: Vouchers (Dillard's) 1946-47 (Box 26)
- Naval War College: Correspondence 1955-68 (Box 26)
- Naval War College: Notes [1955-65] (Box 26)
- Naval War College: Teaching Material 1964-68 (Box 26)
- Note Cards: Book Extracts for Researcher (kept in a file) n.d. (Box 26)
- Note Cards: Miscellaneous n.d. (Box 26)
- Notes [some for a 1977 Conference] 1977, n.d. (Box 26)
- Notes and Drafts 1980 (Box 26)
- Notes: "Excerpts" [1955-65] (Box 27)
- Notes: "Fragmentary Quotes" [1937-1961] (Box 27)
- Notes: "Lectures-1947" 1947 (Box 27)